### **Bernard Cultess**

Union, NJ 07083

973-477-2165 | berniecultess@gmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/bcultess

### **SUMMARY**

A seasoned UI Web Developer with extensive and well-rounded experience in the healthcare and auction house environment. Known for being an eager and outgoing developer, with a knack for learning new technology and having a strong sense of aesthetics and interaction.

**SKILLS** 

Web Technologies: HTML/HTML 5, CSS/ CSS 3, JavaScript, SCSS

**Design Tools**: Animate, Photoshop, Sketch, Zeplin, Illustrator, InDesign

Tools & Databases: phpMyAdmin, MySQL

Project Management: Trello, JIRA
Methodologies: Agile
Version Control: GIT. SVN

IDE: Visual Studio Code, Eclipse, Sublime Text, Notepad++

JavaScript Framework: AngularJS, React, TypeScript

Theming: Material-UI CRM Platform: Salesforce CMS: WordPress

EXPERIENCE

IQVIA, Warren, NJ April 2015 – July 2019

## **Software Engineer II**

Front-end developer for the graphical user interface for Mobile Intelligence updates.

- Designed and developed innovative UI and services for proprietary applications.
- Worked on a highly Agile, engaged and motivated development team.
- Participated in all stages of development life cycles.
- Responsible for maintenance of applications with technologies such as HTML, SCSS, JavaScript, Material-UI, React, Typescript, Photoshop, Sketch, and Zeplin.
- Performed code review of other team members.
- Researched new technologies, identified and learned best practices, adapted quickly and provided technical guidance to other team members.
- Collaborated with leadership to implement codes that were lighter and cleaner.
- Managed multiple bug issues and site improvements that were tracked using JIRA Bug Tracking system.

# CVS Health, Florham Park, NJ

August 2014 – March 2015

# **UI Developer**

Front-end developer with a designers eye and understands the user experience who will develop the prototype website for business.

- Updated and maintained mobile interfaces using technologies such as HTML 5, CSS 3, LESS, JavaScript, and AngularJS.
- Participated in adding new feature Buy Online, Pick Up in Store (BOPUS) to CVS mobile app.
- Worked on a mini prototype demo for CVS Caremark Specialty.

- Created multiple images in different sizes to cater to all mobile devices using Illustrator and Photoshop.
- Created a demo site that mimicked the CVS Caremark desktop version.

# Sotheby's, New York, NY Application Engineer

August 2004 - January 2014

Developer responsible for designing, developing and implementing programs and applications.

- Updated and maintained websites using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript completing tasks in an agile environment, ahead of time and ensuring efficiency.
- Assisted in the implementation and testing of Adobe CQ Content Management System (CMS) as well as made the website responsive using frameworks such as Bootstrap.
- Developed editable components for CMS so producers can work more productively and keep Sotheby's website maintained.
- Developed an iPad app for Sotheby's Catalogue using Adobe Digital Publishing Suite (DPS), XML, JSON, HTML 5 and CSS 3 technologies.
- Also, worked on multiple bug issues and site improvements that were tracked using JIRA Bug Tracking system.

### **EDUCATION**

Internet Application Developer Certification International Webmasters Association (IWA) Corporate Webmaster Certification Sysoft Center for Software Excellence, Iselin, NJ

Bachelor of Science, Mechanical Engineering Michigan State University, East Lansing, MI